# Pallavi Rane

A Human Resources Leader with 15 years of experience working in Multinational and Multi-Cultural environment as Generalist and Corporate HR profile. Handling all facets of HR with MNCs. Sound exposure in Talent Acquisition, Leadership & Executive Hiring, Volume Hiring, Employee Life Cycle, Talent Management, Employee Engagement, PMS, and Learning & Development. Closely worked with business leaders. Work closely with Printing & Packaging, Pharmaceutical Industry, also work with Various BMC projects for their Healthcare division. and was responsible for setting-up complete HR function as well as creating HR team to respond to business growth.

### pallavi.rane2008@gmail.com 9619833128



# **Roles & Responsibilities**

## **Talent Acquisition**

 Responsible for end to end hiring process for PAN India Business Units screening, negotiating with candidates, and hiring them as per company's guidelines. Majorly worked upon, 3D Modeler, CGI

Supervisor, Artist, Retouchers profile. A complete new team of 150 employees hired for 3D – CGI department.

- Strengthening Talent Acquisition capability for India.
- Develop recruitment sourcing strategy including direct sourcing, agency usage, Employee Referral Programs, Internal Job Posting, leveraging social media etc.
- · Active participation in Campus Recruitment
- · Candidate on boarding and induction

#### **Performance Management**

- Practicing PMS process, policies & promotion guidelines
- Coordinating with the employees and managers regarding PMS process, based KPAs and KPIs.
- Ensuring the Objective/Goal Setting process completion for entire organization
- Half yearly review of performance of employees, tracking nonperformers monthly.

### **Workforce Planning and HR Budgeting**

- Discuss Strategic Workforce Plans with the Functional Heads and forecast hiring needs.
- Carry out the annual HR Budgeting exercise and get the same approved by the Managing Director
- Implement Performance Plan and monitor sales performance against budgets.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Head - HR

Comart Group of Companies - Mumbai (Sep 2021 - Till Today)

Assistant Manager - HR

Alia Group's Brand World – Mumbai (May 2018 – July 2020)

## Assistant Manager - HR

Comart Lithographers Mumbai (March 2013 to April 2018)

#### **HR Executive**

Ascender Pvt LTD (November 2011 to March 2013)

#### **HR Executive and Admin**

MDACS (WHO – BMC Project) (August 2007 to May 2011)

#### **HR Policies and Processes**

- Formulation and execution of policies on company level with regards to discipline, work hygiene and prevention of sexual harassment
- Update policies periodically as per Management' requirement.
- Develop/design employee Policy handbook.
- Preparing Organogram/Organization charts for Department as per Management's requirement

# ERP, ULTIPRO, SPIN, HGS Payroll – HRSM

- Detailed functional and operational knowledge of Travel, Time management, in HRMS
- Administer, manage, and update employee master payroll and HRSM for new joinees and update the master as per the organizational changes.
- Managing Organogram on periodic basis as per management's approval

### **Training and Development**

- Identifying training needs based on the performance assessments of the employees and department requirement.
- Analysing Skill Gaps for "Training Need Identification" by coordinating with HODs and employees to understand the training needs.
- Maintain & execute training calendar.

# **Employee Engagement**

- Facilitate open communication in the organization, town hall, Questioner forum.
- Employees to write their own job description.
- Rewords and recognition.

## **ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION**

- MBA HR Mumbai University
- BSc. Chemistry Mumbai University
- DMLT SIES Institute of Management Studies

#### **HR and ISO Audits**

 Facing ISO and HR Auditors and making sure that the SOP's and the processes for HR are followed and implemented within HR.

### **COMPUTE SKILLS**

- Diploma in Office Automation & Graphics
- · Dos, Windows, MS-Office, Ms-Word, Ms-Excel
- · Page Maker, Coral Draw, Photoshop,